davidlloyd.co.uk 2019-12-14

# Privacy Policy | David Lloyd Clubs

**DAVID LLOYD CLUBS PRIVACY NOTICE  **

This is our Privacy Notice. In it you can find all the information you need about how we use your personal data.

**WHO WE ARE**

David Lloyd Clubs is a brand owned by David Lloyd Leisure Limited, whose registered office is located at The Hangar, Mosquito Way, Hatfield Business Park, Hatfield, Hertfordshire, AL10 9AX, registered in England under Company No 1516226. 

**PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

We may collect and process the following data about you summarised by category:

**Members, non-members and guests**

_Contact and identification details_

We record your name, postal and email addresses, telephone number(s) and contact preferences when you enquire on our website or when you sign in as a guest at one of our clubs. If one of our members makes a booking for you as a guest or recommends you as a friend they may provide us with your name, phone number and email address. 

_Session and device details_

We record your name, email address, your device’s MAC address and IP address when you log on to our wireless network.

_Payment details_

If you pay for goods and services in our clubs by card we record your payment card details.

_Usage and attendance details_

We may capture your image on CCTV when you visit one of our clubs. 

If you use our website we record information about the URL you came from, your device’s IP address, your browser type and information about where your device is located.

If you use one of our spas we keep a record of your booking and a consultation card which holds information about your general health and treatment.

_Correspondence and incidents_

If you contact us we may keep a record of that correspondence and any comments and responses you submit via surveys and our feedback system.

If you or your child is involved in an incident at one of our clubs, we will record details of the incident.

_Details about your child_

If your child attends a supervised activity at one of our clubs we keep a record of their attendance, emergency contact details and essential health information e.g. allergies.

**Members**

In addition, if you are a member of one of our clubs, we may collect and process the following data about you summarised by category:

_Contact and identification details_

We record your date of birth and gender. We may also take your photograph when you join. We store your user name and password if you register online with us. If you give us evidence in support of your membership application we will keep it on file.

_Session and device details_

If you use our mobile app we record your usage data and location (if your device settings allow).

_Payment details_

We keep details of your membership package and fees for you and others linked to your membership and the payments you make to us.  If you pay your membership and other fees by direct debit we keep a record of your bank details.

_Usage and attendance details_

We keep a record of when you swipe in to any David Lloyd Club using your membership card. We also hold information about your racquets and class bookings. We keep a note of vouchers and guest passes issued to you. We keep a record of your health and fitness goals if you choose to share them with us.

_Your personal circumstances_

If you give us evidence of relocation, redundancy or a medical condition in line with our cancellation or suspension policy we will keep it on file.

_Information we receive from third parties_

If your membership is connected to your employer they will give us your employee number. If you connect your wearable device to any of our equipment in club we will automatically receive data from it. If your device is registered with us, we may also receive usage data from the supplier. 

_Details held by other service providers_

We may make available to our members some services which are provided by other companies. In each case, they are responsible for telling you about any personal data which they collect. Examples include Boditrax, MyZone, PlaySight,

**Non-members and guests**

If you are not a member we use the information that you provide or that we collect in line with this Privacy Policy and our Website Terms of Use on the basis of our legitimate business interests unless otherwise stated for the following purposes:

_Contact and identification details_

We use your contact details to respond to your enquiry or manage your booking and to let you know about our products and services which may be of interest (including through the use of email, phone and text if you have agreed to receive this information from us electronically).

_Session and device details_

We use session and device details to manage access to our network and to make our website easier to use.

_Payment details_

We use your payment card details to collect payment for goods and services.

_Usage and attendance details_

We use CCTV for the prevention and detection of crime and the health and safety of guests, members and staff. We use information about website usage to make our website easier to navigate.

We use the information you give us when visiting the spa to manage our bookings and to inform our therapists when offering treatments. We need your permission to process information about your health and we will be unable to offer any treatments without it.

_Correspondence and incidents_

We use your feedback to improve our facilities and services and to assist us in dealing with any query you may have. We record details of incidents to comply with our obligations under health and safety legislation.

_Details about your child_

We use the information you give us about your child to safeguard their health and safety.

**Members and ex-members**

If you are a member we use the information that you provide or that we collect in line with this Privacy Policy, our Terms and Conditions of Membership and our Website Terms of Use on the basis of our contract with you and our legitimate business interests unless otherwise stated for the following purposes:

_Contact and identification details_

We use your contact details to register you with David Lloyd Clubs, to set up and manage your membership account and to administer our services in accordance with our terms and conditions; to contact you about changes to facilities, fees and membership terms; and to let you know about our products and services which may be of interest (including through the use of email and text if you have agreed to receive this information from us electronically).

_Session and device details_

We use your session and device details to manage access to our network; to make our website easier to use and to alert you about bookings and classes through our mobile app.

_Payment details_

We use your payment details to collect membership fees and other payments due from you in line with our terms and conditions; to take advice and action in relation to the collection of debts and to assist us in resolving any disputes.

_Usage and attendance details_

We use CCTV for the prevention and detection of crime and the health and safety of guests, members and staff. We use information about website usage to make our website easier to navigate.

We use usage and attendance data to administer our booking policy and the terms and conditions on the use of our facilities; to improve your experience of our facilities and to tailor our communications with you.

_Your personal circumstances_

We use the information you give us to administer our policy on suspension or cancellation.

_Correspondence and incidents_

We use your feedback to improve our facilities and services and to assist us in dealing with any query you may have. We record details of incidents to comply with our obligations under health and safety legislation.

_Details about your child_

We use the information you give us about your child to safeguard their health and safety.

_Information we receive from third parties_

We use data from your wearable device to improve your experience of our facilities. We use information supplied by your employer to collect payment if your membership is paid for by them.

We may also use the information that you provide or that we collect in any other way as described to you at the time of collection of your personal data.

**SPECIAL CATEGORIES OF PERSONAL DATA**

We may process information about your health or your child’s health, for example to ensure the safety of your child or to comply with our obligations under health and safety law. Where the processing is to provide a service to you, we will always ask for your agreement. If you are not happy for us to have this information you do not have to agree, and you can change your mind at any time, but this may mean that your child is unable to take part in a supervised activity.

**SHARING YOUR INFORMATION WITH OTHERS**

We value your privacy and do not sell your information to any third parties under any circumstances.

We may give information about you to the following third parties, who may use it for the same purposes as us and also as set out below:

We share data with our agents, contractors and employees in the country where you are a member to administer your membership, your account, and any products and services provided to you now or in the future.

We may share data with agents and employees of any other companies in the European Economic Area in the same group of companies as David Lloyd Leisure Group Limited to administer your membership, your account, and any products and services provided to you now or in the future. 

Sometimes we may transfer your personal information outside the European Economic Area (EEA).  Depending on your relationship with us this may include:

transfers to Vitality’s offices outside the EEA (e.g. South Africa) if you are a Vitality member;

transfers to the US where either we or our agents make use of services that are hosted there.

If we do so we will make sure that suitable safeguards are in place, for example by using approved contractual agreements.

We share your card and bank details with our secure payment providers to process card transactions and direct debit payments.

We share your contact details and preferences with mailing houses, our marketing agencies, systems providers and other distributors for the distribution of information to you.

We share contact and identification details with our media agents, search engine providers and social media platforms so that we can tailor our communications to the right audience.

We may share attendance details with your employer or flexible benefits provider if your membership is arranged through them.

We may share your data with anyone to whom we transfer or may transfer our rights and duties under our agreement with you, if we have a duty to do so or if the law allows us to do so. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction. We share data with third parties who will help process or administer our services or who will provide advice and take action in relation to the collection of debts.

**HOW LONG WE KEEP YOUR INFORMATION**

We keep the information that you provide or that we collect only for as long as we need to in line with the reason it was collected. More detail is given below for each category of information.

**Non-members and guests**

We keep your contact details for up to four years after your first enquiry. We keep enough information to record your communication preferences indefinitely in order to avoid sending you unwanted information in future.

We keep session and device details for 24 hours to avoid you having to log in again on the same day.

We keep correspondence for seven years in case you contact us again about the same subject.

**Members and ex-members**

We keep your contact and identification details, usage and attendance details and information about your personal circumstances during your membership and for seven years after it ends so we can respond in the event of any query about your membership. We may keep certain information for longer than this if we have a compelling reason for keeping it.

We keep enough information to record your communication preferences indefinitely in order to avoid sending you unwanted information in future.

We keep correspondence for seven years after you leave in case you contact us again about the same subject. We keep details of incidents for three years after the date of the incident.

We keep payment details during your membership and for seven years after you leave in line with the BACS code of practice.

CCTV recordings are deleted automatically after 40 days unless they are retained in connection with an investigation, in which case we keep them until after the investigation is concluded.

We do not store any data received from your wearable device.

We store details about your child for a year. We will ask you for a new health and safety form for your child each year.

**YOUR RIGHTS**

You have the right to make a request for a copy of the personal data that we keep about you or to correct the details that we hold about you. We will respond within one month.

If you would like to know what personal information we hold about you, or would like us to correct the details we hold about you, you should write to the address below or email **privacy@davidlloyd.co.uk** , enclosing proof of your identity (such as a copy of your passport or driving licence) and asking to see your personal information or asking us to correct the relevant information. You will have to give us enough information so we can identify the personal information you have asked to see or have corrected. We do not have to respond to your request until you have given us the information we need. We will contact you within one month of your request or, where we have asked for further information to identify you, within one month of receiving such information.

You have the right to receive the information in a portable electronic form. If your request is by email from the address that we hold for you we will respond by email to that address.

You have the right to ask us to erase your personal data under certain circumstances.

You have the right to ask us to stop processing your personal data where the processing is based on our legitimate interests. This does not include processing which is in line with our Terms and Conditions of Membership, for example payment processing. If we believe we have a legitimate reason for processing your personal information including for the defence of any legal claims we may decline your request.

Under certain circumstances, for example if we decline your request to stop processing, you have the right to ask us to restrict the processing of your personal data.

**UPDATING YOUR MARKETING PREFERENCES**

We may use your personal information to provide you with marketing information about our products and services such as newsletters, product updates, surveys, company announcements and invites to events that will be of interest to you.

You can opt out of receiving marketing messages at any time by following the unsubscribe links located within any electronic communication from us. You can also contact your local club by phone or email using the contact details on our website [www.davidlloyd.co.uk.](http://www.davidlloyd.co.uk/)

Please note that, even if you opt out of receiving marketing messages, we may still send you service related communications where necessary.

**YOUR RIGHT TO COMPLAIN**

If you are unhappy about how your personal data is being processed you should raise your concern with us first - see “Contacting Us” below. If you are not happy with the way that we deal with your concerns you can contact the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) at ico.org.uk

**COOKIES**

When you visit one of our websites or mobile applications, we may send you a cookie. A cookie is a small file that can be placed on your computer's hard disk or mobile device for record keeping purposes and we may use them to do a number of things:

Cookies help us to recognise you when you next visit one of our websites and note the advertisements displayed to you. This allows us to tailor the advertisements we provide to your preferences. We may use the services of third party ad servers for this purpose.

Cookies may be used to compile anonymous statistics related to the take up or use of services, or to patterns of browsing. A third party collects such data on our behalf to measure web site performance. Information collected is aggregated for reporting purposes. No personally identifiable information is collected by this service. The use of this service assists us in measuring and improving the structure and ease of use of our web sites.

If you do not wish to use cookies, you may de-activate cookies in your web-browser or reject the creation of cookies. You may wish to seek technical assistance from your browser provider if you do not know how to do this. For more information on cookies and how we use them visit [**www.davidlloyd.co.uk/policies/cookie-policy**](http://www.davidlloyd.co.uk/policies/cookie-policy)  
David Lloyd Leisure cannot be responsible for any technical faults or failures to your system.

**CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY**

We may update this Privacy Policy at any time. Any such changes will be posted on our website. If you continue to use our services after we have changed this Privacy Policy, the updated version will apply.

**SECURITY AND LIABILITY**

In order to comply with our obligations under Data Protection law, we will protect your personal data from unauthorised access, misuse, alteration or loss by using commercially reasonable security measures. Any payment transactions will be encrypted using SSL technology.

Nothing in this policy in any way excludes or limits our liability for negligence causing death or personal injury or for fraudulent misrepresentation.

Unfortunately the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of any data transmitted to our site; any transmission will be at your own risk.

We are not responsible or liable to you for any loss or damage you may suffer or incur in connection with your use of our online services which is caused by any event beyond our reasonable control including the electronic transmission of information, content, material and data over the internet and the interception and decryption of it by others.

We are not responsible to you for any losses or damage you may suffer caused by any distributed denial-of-service attack, or any viruses, trojans, worms, logic bombs or other material which is malicious or technologically harmful and which may infect, contaminate or damage your computer equipment or computer programs, or cause damage to software or damage to or loss of data unless caused by our negligence. You should ensure that you use appropriate virus checking software and firewalls. 

Whilst we have taken reasonable steps to ensure the accuracy, currency, correctness and completeness of the information contained on our website, we do not check, review, monitor, verify or endorse any information, content, material or data collected from or provided by third parties which is displayed on or is otherwise available from our website or any third party websites or services which you can access from our site. We are not responsible to you for any loss, damage or injury you may suffer or incur in connection with such information, content, material or data. It is your responsibility to check that such information, content, material or data is accurate, current, correct and complete.

If your personal data is accessed by an unauthorised third party, we will not be responsible for any direct or indirect damage caused as a result of such unauthorised access.

Where we have given you a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share your password with anyone.

Whilst we take all reasonable steps to ensure that our website continues to be available there may be times when it is not available. This may be for reasons relating to the maintenance of, or alterations to, the website or for reasons beyond our control. We are not responsible to you if the website is unavailable.

**CONTACTING US**

All questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy should be addressed to [privacy@davidlloyd.co.uk](mailto:privacy@davidlloyd.co.uk)

Or by writing to:  David Lloyd Leisure Limited, The Hangar, Mosquito Way, Hatfield Business Park, Hatfield, Hertfordshire, AL10 9AX
